softserveinc.com 2018-09-02

# Privacy Policy | SoftServe

Privacy Policy

Our privacy practices are designed to provide a high level of protection for your personal data

This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by SoftServe when you access the website at [www.softserveinc.com](https://www.softserveinc.com/) (the “website”), all related websites (subdomains), other services provided by SoftServe on which a link to this Privacy Policy is displayed, and all other communications with you through from written or oral means, such as email or phone. It also describes how the information will be used, how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of information and how to get in touch with us if you need. Our privacy practices are designed to provide a high level of protection for your personal data. We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. This Policy is incorporated into, and is subject to, the Terms and Conditions of use available on this website. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data before browsing this website.

## Information we collect about you

We collect information about you when you submit the information through the form on the website or otherwise make the information available for us (by phone, email, etc.). For example, we collect your full name, email, company name and address, job title, phone number and additional information you provide us when you request receiving whitepaper or contacting you directly. We collect your full name, email, phone number, info source from which you received information about SoftServe, information contained in your CV, industry, position and additional information you provide us when applying for a vacancy. In cases where you would like to join us as freelancer, we will collect your full name, email, phone number, type of engagement, your professional profile, hourly rate and additional information you provide us. You can also register your personal account where you want to apply for a vacancy, register for IT Academy courses, track the status of your requests, and contact IT Academy recruiters. In this case we will collect your full name, email, phone number, date of birth, country, city, your language skills and information contained in your CV. In cases where it is specifically stated that some data is not mandatory, you are free not to submit this data. Our website is not directed to children under the age of 16, and we do not knowingly collect personal data from children under the age of 16. If you are under 16 years of age, then please do not use or access the website at any time or in any manner.

## Cookies

We collect anonymous information from visits to our website to help us provide better customer service. For example, we record certain automatically collected information, which include IP address, web browser, OS, the web pages or sites visited just before or just after using the website, keep track of the domains from which you visit and we also measure your activity on the website, but we do so in ways that keep the information anonymous. SoftServe uses this data to analyze trends and statistics and to help us provide better customer service. Cookies can be used to provide you with tailored information from a website. You can determine if and how a cookie will be accepted by configuring your browser, which is installed in the computer you are using to access the website. If you desire, you can change those configurations in your browser to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is sent, or to reject all cookies.

## How the information about you is used

We use the information that we collect to operate and maintain our website and to provide the services and information that you request, to allow you contact us, provide access to requested whitepaper, respond to your comments, questions and concerns. We will also process your job applications where you applied for a vacancy or would like to join us as freelancer. When you register your personal account, we will process your data in order to provide you information about vacancies, IT Academy courses you have attended and information about new courses we are planning to conduct. We will also send you updates on latest products, event announcements, and thought leadership or notifications of company news, hot vacancies and marketing offers where we have obtained your consent or you give us your email address expressly to receive marketing. If you have consented to receive marketing, you have a right at any time to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes. You may unsubscribe or update your email preferences at any time by following the instructions contained within the email or by sending an email to the address provided in the Contacting Us section. We can also process your personal data if it is necessary for us to administer the contractual relationship between ourselves and our suppliers/members in connection with the performance of a contract. Where you are an existing customer of SoftServe and we have an existing relationship with you, or we reasonable believe you can be our customer, we will process your data based on legitimate interest and send you information about products and services, events or other material that will be relevant to your individual interests and process your personal information to make sure we send you only relevant, targeted information. You can opt-out of this at any time by following the instructions contained within the email or by sending an email to the address provided in the Contacting Us section.

## Your rights

If you wish to access or amend any personal data we hold about you, or to request that we delete or transfer any information about you may contact us as set forth in the Contacting Us section. At any time, you may also object to processing of your personal data or ask us to restrict processing of your personal data. If you believe your right to privacy granted by applicable data protection laws has been infringed upon, please contact us as set forth in the Contacting Us section. You also have a right to lodge a complaint with data protection authorities.

## Other websites

This website contains links to other websites. This Privacy Policy only applies to this website so when you link to other websites you should read their own privacy policies. SoftServe is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

## Data processing and transfer

In addition to SoftServe, in some cases, personal data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the website or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, hosting providers, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as data processors by SoftServe. These third parties may have access to, or process personal data as part of providing those services for us. Our contracts with them require them to maintain the confidentiality of such information. Your information collected by SoftServe may be stored and processed in the Europe, United States or Ukraine or any other country in which SoftServe or its subsidiaries, affiliates or service providers maintain facilities. SoftServe may transfer information that we collect about you, including personal data, to affiliated entities, or to other third parties across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. We will comply with GDPR requirements providing adequate protection for the transfer of personal data from Europe to third parties, in particular, will enter into the standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing and processing.

## Integrated Services

You may be given the option to fill in the contact form through the use of your user name and passwords for certain services provided by third parties (each, an “Integrated Service”), such as through the use of your LinkedIn or Facebook account, or otherwise have the option to authorize an Integrated Service to provide personal data or other information to us. By authorizing us to connect with an Integrated Service, you authorize us to access and store your name, email address(es), date of birth, gender, current city, profile picture URL, and other information that the Integrated Service makes available to us, and to use and disclose it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You should check your privacy settings on each Integrated Service to understand what information that Integrated Service makes available to us, and make changes as appropriate. Please review each Integrated Service’s terms of use and privacy policies carefully before using their services and connecting us.

## Data retention

We keep your personal data for as long as it is necessary to do so to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected as described above. The criteria we use to determine data retention periods for personal data includes the following: retention in accordance with legal and regulatory requirements. We may retain and use your information in order to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, prevent abuse.

## Security

We endeavour to use appropriate technical and physical security measures to protect your personal data which is transmitted, stored or otherwise processed by us, from accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorised disclosure of, or access.

## Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time in our sole discretion. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy they will be posted on the website so that you are always aware of what information we gather, how we might use that information and in what circumstances we may disclose it.

In the event you have any questions, comments and requests about the information set out in this Privacy Policy, please contact us by submitting the form below.

Please provide correct email

Required

Please verify captcha

### Great job

Your message has been sent! We`ll get back to you very soon!

## Controller

For the purposes of the data protection legislation, the Data Controller is IT-Technoresource d/b/a SoftServe (hereunder referred to as “SoftServe”), a company registered in Ukraine, having its registered office at Lviv region, Pustomyty, Glinska 14 street. We have designated an EU representative, the contact details of which are the following: SoftServe Poland Sp. z.o.o., a company registered in Poland, having its registered office at Al. Wiśniowa 1, 53-137 Wrocław.
